<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>String Bulbs</title>
    <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on String Bulbs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:57:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wheatdog.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>devember 4</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/05/devember-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:57:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/05/devember-4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devember Day 3 - Basic MultiPlayer Movement</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/03/devember-day-3---basic-multiplayer-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 22:51:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/03/devember-day-3---basic-multiplayer-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s code is on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wheatdog/wastale/tree/devember_3&#34;&gt;this tag&lt;/a&gt;. The complete
code can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wheatdog/wastale&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Let&amp;rsquo;s draw some rectangle on the screen. You can check out &lt;code&gt;DrawRect&lt;/code&gt;
function. Be careful that the coordinates of angles in the rectangle might sit
outside of the screen. This might cause to memory access violation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Q2K2vRs.gif?1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, it is about physic of motion.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?v&amp;amp;space;=&amp;amp;space;v_0&amp;amp;space;&amp;amp;plus;&amp;amp;space;at&#34; alt=&#34;v = v_0 + at&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?x&amp;amp;space;=&amp;amp;space;x_0&amp;amp;space;&amp;amp;plus;&amp;amp;space;v_0t&amp;amp;space;&amp;amp;plus;&amp;amp;space;0.5at&#34; alt=&#34;x = x_0 + v_0t + \frac{1}{2}at&#34; /&gt;

Also, change the unit from pixel to meter. You can feel that motion is much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/mOQgHIO.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each entry of &lt;code&gt;player_info&lt;/code&gt; struct array store the information of each player.
Now, we have multiplayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/m7jKV9f.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devember Day 2 - Live Code Editing</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/02/devember-day-2---live-code-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 22:47:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/02/devember-day-2---live-code-editing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s code is on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wheatdog/wastale/tree/devember_2&#34;&gt;this tag&lt;/a&gt;. The complete
code can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wheatdog/wastale&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most coolest thing I did today is &amp;ldquo;Live Code Editing&amp;rdquo; that Casey mentioned
in Handmade Hero week 5. The basic idea is to make platform independent code be
another translation unit, and compile it to a DLL. Then, we can dynamically load
it in the Win32 platform code. By doing so, we can change our game code without
reopening the executable file at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/8EWjY6u.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might implement the &amp;ldquo;Loop editing&amp;rdquo; feature after I got some entities on the
screen. Tomorrow, I will start doing some game code. Until then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devember Day 1 - Basic Win32 Layer</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/01/devember-day-1---basic-win32-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 23:17:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/12/01/devember-day-1---basic-win32-layer/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I spent some time reviewing the construction of Win32 prototyping
layer mentioned in Handmade Hero weeks 1 through 5. In those weeks, Casey talk
about some basic stuff that a game need - Graphic, Sound, and Input. If you are
interested in detail, I would recommend you to watch
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hero.handmadedev.org/jace/guide/&#34;&gt;Day 1 to 25 of Handmade Hero&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most codes of &lt;code&gt;win32_wastale.*&lt;/code&gt; are as same as the codes in &lt;code&gt;win32_handmade.*&lt;/code&gt;.
The most different part is the sound. I will talk about in the rest of the
article. By the way, the source code of wastale is on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wheatdog/wastale&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; if you want to take a look.
Today&amp;rsquo;s code is on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wheatdog/wastale/tree/devember_1&#34;&gt;this tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;xaudio2:38d4082b4e2ef27c7672bc7e5af08564&#34;&gt;XAudio2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of using DirectSound, I choose XAudio2. There is only one ring buffer in
DirectSound. When we have reached the end of the buffer, we start from the
beginning. However, in XAudio2, we can submit several &lt;code&gt;XAUDIO2_BUFFER&lt;/code&gt; through
&lt;code&gt;IXAudio2SourceVoice::SubmitSourceBuffer&lt;/code&gt; method. Basicly, it is like a queue.
Each time we reach the end of a buffer, it will start playing the next buffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can reduce the audio latency by keeping the same number of samples in the
queue. For example, Red line represent the frame boundary. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that we run
in 30 frames per second and have 48000 samples per second. Therefore, there are
1600 samples per frame. Every time we write, we will make sure that the number
of samples in the audio queue are 2400, that is the number of samples in one and
a half frames.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/BgS6Lj&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5697/23152009310_c431845d73_o.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
Brown arrow represent the time that we first write to the sound buffer, and the
brown rounded rectangle near the black line represent the samples we write. Next
time we update samples at the time green arrow point to. To keep the number of
samples in the queue, we will only need to write the number of samples that
green rounded rectangle stand for. If we can update samples in the audio buffer
just in the middle of the frame like arrows in the image above. We can generate
enough samples for next frame and those samples will be played right on the
frame boundary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, first we cannot guarantee we always update samples at the same
time. Therefore, sound boundary may not line up with the frame boudary, which I
think is fine. Second, &lt;code&gt;IXAudio2SourceVoice::GetState&lt;/code&gt; cannot return the exactly
samples we just played without using callback. Its granularity is 480 samples in
my machine. That means that we might fill less sample than what we really need
to. The worst case is that we will have the gap of 480 samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easy way to solve this problem is to make the number we want to keep in the
queue larger. Another solution will be using callback which I am really not
familiar with. I think the latency right now is fine for a prototyping
layer. Therefore, I will move on to deal with other problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tomorrow:38d4082b4e2ef27c7672bc7e5af08564&#34;&gt;Tomorrow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to implement &amp;ldquo;Live Code Editing&amp;rdquo; feature Casey talked about in
Handmade Hero Week 5 tomorrow. Then, maybe start game engine code exploration
Thursday. Until then!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Devember challenge</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/14/the-devember-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 13:40:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/14/the-devember-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I, Tim Liou, will participate to the next Devember. My Devember will be
programming a part of Wastale, a game project. I promise I will program for my
Devember for at least an hour, every day of the next December. I will also write
a daily public devlog and will make the produced code publicly available on the
internet. No matter what, I will keep my promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content above is the contract of &lt;a href=&#34;http://devember.org/&#34;&gt;Devember&lt;/a&gt;, a really
interesting challenge in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detail:68a5841ae5e350aae7d7c051b365f42f&#34;&gt;Detail&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wastale is a developing game inspired by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://handmadehero.org/&#34;&gt;Handmade Hero&lt;/a&gt;. This game will focus on big, various
enemies and different kinds of weapons. I hope this game can give players
hunting excitement but not in mission-based. There are still lots of game design
decisions need to make. Obviously, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about them now. In
December, I will first build up the minimum windows platform layer just like
Handmade Hero did. Then, I will implement some basic stuff for a platformer
game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;goals:68a5841ae5e350aae7d7c051b365f42f&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, following are my Devember goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Windows platform layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World/Map handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entity handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dj-play-the-music:68a5841ae5e350aae7d7c051b365f42f&#34;&gt;DJ! Play the music&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really love the idea of Devember. Let&amp;rsquo;s start the party.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The beginning of Tab</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/11/the-beginning-of-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/11/the-beginning-of-tab/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction:21722be5d1f6ebe0b44bb8f424f9d174&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, this is Venses Tab. When I was in junior high school, I started listening
electronic music. At that time, I quite enjoyed the music taking me floating
above mind sea. My mp3 was used to load lots of industrial-loud electronic noise,
you should wonder that why a boy had this strange passion on such noise in his
early life. You know what, because the beats are truly epic! Until now, I still
love plugging earphone, wandering in digital labyrinth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;play-around:21722be5d1f6ebe0b44bb8f424f9d174&#34;&gt;Play around&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of my college&amp;rsquo;s life, I ask myself, &amp;ldquo;How about I compose my own
music?&amp;ldquo;. Thanks to the prosperity of clubs in my college, there is a club
teaching me composing digital music using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ableton-Live&#34;&gt;Ableton Live&lt;/a&gt;, and also I learn
some DJ skills. When time goes on, the laziness of attitude and loads of
assignment let me often get tired of practicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;motivation:21722be5d1f6ebe0b44bb8f424f9d174&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, Tim and I found Stringbulbs. We have lots of memories of thinking game
ideas when we were little. This time, in November, we launch a new project for
our first game. In this team, Tim is as programmer, and I am as soundtrack
producer, maybe sometimes help Tim program a little bit, ugh&amp;hellip;, all I want to
say is I hope this work can motivate me to find my lost passion about music
composition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;goal:21722be5d1f6ebe0b44bb8f424f9d174&#34;&gt;Goal?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before 2015 ends, I promise I will finish a set for DJ performance and one
experimental music soundtrack. Also, in leisure time, I will post some my
opinion and thought about music and project here, hope you guys have a nice
day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a professional game</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/09/make-a-professional-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 21:51:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/09/make-a-professional-game/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mollyrocket.com/casey/about.html&#34;&gt;Casey Muratori&lt;/a&gt; launched a brilliant
project &lt;a href=&#34;http://handmadehero.org/&#34;&gt;Handmade Hero&lt;/a&gt; last year. I still remember
how excited I was when I watched the very first episode of Handmade Hero. After
following 70 episodes, I start thinking what I could use from what I learned. I
am not saying I will stop following this project or I have leaned enough from
it. I just mean that I am the kind of person can learn more by doing. Therefore,
I decide to make my own game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-now:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;Why now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a college student right now. Basically, I can say this period of time is the
most free time in my whole life. I can learn whatever I want and do whatever I
want. One reason why I choose computer science as my college major is my passion
for indie games. Indie games truly rock my soul. I saw something very unique in
them. Unlike AAA games, I can feel real &amp;ldquo;connect&amp;rdquo; between players and game
designers. That definitely is what I want to do in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-genre-will-this-game-be:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;What genre will this game be?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love puzzle games like &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/26800/&#34;&gt;Braid&lt;/a&gt; and
roguelike games like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/113200/&#34;&gt;The Binding of Isaac&lt;/a&gt;. As my first
game, this game might be a 2D roguelike game. When I was a junior high school
student, I really enjoyed the excitement of fighting huge enemies in Monster
Hunter but sucked at the feature of collecting materials for forging weapons. In
this game, I will get rid of the concept of collecting and focus on the weapon
system and huge enemies. I will talk about them in the later posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;goal:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish this game before I graduate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship on Windows and Linux at least since I only have machines with these
operation systems now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;keep-going-on:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;Keep going on&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actions speak louder than words. Procrastination is the horrible enemy. I will
post something new about Wastale at least every two weeks. You have my word.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>