<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wastale on String Bulbs</title>
    <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/tags/wastale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wastale on String Bulbs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 13:40:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wheatdog.github.io/tags/wastale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Devember challenge</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/14/the-devember-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 13:40:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/14/the-devember-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I, Tim Liou, will participate to the next Devember. My Devember will be
programming a part of Wastale, a game project. I promise I will program for my
Devember for at least an hour, every day of the next December. I will also write
a daily public devlog and will make the produced code publicly available on the
internet. No matter what, I will keep my promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content above is the contract of &lt;a href=&#34;http://devember.org/&#34;&gt;Devember&lt;/a&gt;, a really
interesting challenge in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detail:68a5841ae5e350aae7d7c051b365f42f&#34;&gt;Detail&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wastale is a developing game inspired by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://handmadehero.org/&#34;&gt;Handmade Hero&lt;/a&gt;. This game will focus on big, various
enemies and different kinds of weapons. I hope this game can give players
hunting excitement but not in mission-based. There are still lots of game design
decisions need to make. Obviously, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about them now. In
December, I will first build up the minimum windows platform layer just like
Handmade Hero did. Then, I will implement some basic stuff for a platformer
game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;goals:68a5841ae5e350aae7d7c051b365f42f&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, following are my Devember goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Windows platform layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World/Map handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entity handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dj-play-the-music:68a5841ae5e350aae7d7c051b365f42f&#34;&gt;DJ! Play the music&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really love the idea of Devember. Let&amp;rsquo;s start the party.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a professional game</title>
      <link>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/09/make-a-professional-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 21:51:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wheatdog.github.io/2015/11/09/make-a-professional-game/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mollyrocket.com/casey/about.html&#34;&gt;Casey Muratori&lt;/a&gt; launched a brilliant
project &lt;a href=&#34;http://handmadehero.org/&#34;&gt;Handmade Hero&lt;/a&gt; last year. I still remember
how excited I was when I watched the very first episode of Handmade Hero. After
following 70 episodes, I start thinking what I could use from what I learned. I
am not saying I will stop following this project or I have leaned enough from
it. I just mean that I am the kind of person can learn more by doing. Therefore,
I decide to make my own game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-now:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;Why now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a college student right now. Basically, I can say this period of time is the
most free time in my whole life. I can learn whatever I want and do whatever I
want. One reason why I choose computer science as my college major is my passion
for indie games. Indie games truly rock my soul. I saw something very unique in
them. Unlike AAA games, I can feel real &amp;ldquo;connect&amp;rdquo; between players and game
designers. That definitely is what I want to do in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-genre-will-this-game-be:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;What genre will this game be?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love puzzle games like &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/26800/&#34;&gt;Braid&lt;/a&gt; and
roguelike games like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/113200/&#34;&gt;The Binding of Isaac&lt;/a&gt;. As my first
game, this game might be a 2D roguelike game. When I was a junior high school
student, I really enjoyed the excitement of fighting huge enemies in Monster
Hunter but sucked at the feature of collecting materials for forging weapons. In
this game, I will get rid of the concept of collecting and focus on the weapon
system and huge enemies. I will talk about them in the later posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;goal:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish this game before I graduate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship on Windows and Linux at least since I only have machines with these
operation systems now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;keep-going-on:d1f10fe31c342e91c05e8b9b34c96106&#34;&gt;Keep going on&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actions speak louder than words. Procrastination is the horrible enemy. I will
post something new about Wastale at least every two weeks. You have my word.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>